(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-07T01:15:19.892075",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
僕たち6人は配信アプリ「ホロキャス」で活動する配信者。
We six are streamers on the streaming app "Holocast."
突然画面に吸い込まれてアプリとつながる謎の世界ホロキャス界に来ちゃった！？
Suddenly sucked into the screen, we ended up in the mysterious Holocast world connected to the app?!
そこでは現実で苦しむ人の魂が怪物化してしまう現象、夢堕ちが起きていた。
There, a phenomenon where people's souls suffering in reality turned into monsters was happening.
怪物コロプサーを倒して、みんなの魂を取り戻さないと！
We have to defeat the monster Coropsars and reclaim everyone's souls!
そうして私たちは魔法少女に変身して戦うことになった。
And so, we transformed into magical girls and had to fight.
みんなの心を助けて夢を応援しよ！
Saving everyone's hearts and cheering on their dreams—
それが魔法少女ホロウィッチ！
that is Magical Girl Holowitch!
私、もっと大人になったら魔法になりたい。
When I grow up, I want to become magic.
もっといろんな人を励げるの…
To be able to encourage so many people...
面倒な仕事、みんな私に押し付けて丸投げして。
Piling all their troublesome work onto me and dumping it.
やったらやったですきかって言って、
Saying whatever they want after I do it—
何なのよ。
What is this?!
みなさん、こんにちは！
Hello everyone!
会場にお越しいただきありがとうございます！
Thank you for coming to the venue!
さて、本日はここからスペシャルの称号…
Now, from here today, special titles...
ちょっと待ってもらおうか！！
Hold on a second!!
ずいぶん人が集まってんじゃねえか。
Looks like quite a lot of people have gathered here.
あなたたち何者ですか？
Who on earth are you guys?
我ら人間どもの欲望と絶望の糞尿箱垂れ流して、夢を堕ちさせる！
Spilling the cesspool of human desires and despair, we make dreams fall!
それが俺たちコロプサー！
That's us, Coropsars!
大変！この時はあの子たちを呼ぶしかない！皆さんも声を揃えて呼んでくださいね！せーの！
Oh no! At a time like this, we have no choice but to call those girls! Everyone, please call out together! Ready, go!
助けて！ホロウィッチ！
Help us, Holowitch!
なんだ？
What?!
この手を差し伸べ、掴んで、握る！天使のホロ、魔法少女、かなた！
Reach out this hand, grasp it, and hold on! Angelic Holo, Magical Girl Kanata!
みんなの願いを叶える祈り、巫女のホロ、魔法少女みこ！
A prayer granting everyone's wishes, Shrine Maiden Holo, Magical Girl Miko!
甘い幸せお裾分け、姫のホロ、魔法少女ルーナ！
Sharing sweet happiness, Princess Holo, Magical Girl Luna!
きらめくお宝ロックオン！海賊のホロ、魔法少女マリン！
Locking onto sparkling treasures! Pirate Holo, Magical Girl Marine!
眠れる深淵のわがままに、魔女のホロ、魔法少女シオン！
Following the selfish whims of the sleeping abyss, Witch Holo, Magical Girl Shion!
荒波を行く半妖の剣、侍のホロ、魔法少女いろは！
A half-youkai sword braving rough seas, Samurai Holo, Magical Girl Iroha!
ホロウィッチ、ドリームキャスト！
Holowitch, Dreamcast!
君に魔法をかけるよ ウィークステイルの夜
Casting magic on you on the night of the weak's tale...
始まりを告げる衝動が響く 気づいた時がいずだっ…
The impulse signaling the beginning echoes, when I realized...
甘くて幸せなこと
I'll make a treat so sweet and full of fun,
隠し味何にしよう
but I wanna hide a little bit of love.
純粋な乙女心
Pure like a gem, a maiden's eager heart,
甘い恋も絡めなくちゃ
gotta mix it all in from the very start.
切なさ重ねてミルフィーユ
Bake a layered mille-feuille with the air I sigh,
酸味も積み上げタルト
and a sour tart of all the hurt inside.
苦味もチョコレートケーキ?
Make it bitter with a chocolate cake, I'll breathe
魔法かけた甘い奇跡
miracles with a spell full of sweet fantasies.
甘さを抑えてビターとか
Should I take sugar away, have bitterness alone?
ミルクなしのコーヒーとか
Kinda like a coffee without milk or foam.
甘いだけじゃ大人になれないの?
If I still don't like the taste, am I not grown?
そんなの絶対に絶対いやだいやだいやだ
No, it can't be! Don't wanna, wanna, wanna!
ねぇあげようか 甘い罠
Hey, fall into my trap, make you want it bad,
ほら罠にしてあげる
now I've caught you in a sugar rush attack.
そんな魔法かけるから ちょっとだけ待たせたげるわ
Wave a magic wand as I sing along to you.
たった一口が足りなくて
Just one big delicious bite won't be enough,
赤いイチゴみたい意地張って
like every strawberry, I'm prideful and stuff.
甘いところなんて見せないわ
Though it may be hard, I can be really sweet,
完全に作るもん 一人でも、でも、でも
and then you'll see you're made for me!
ねぇ、気づいてるんでしょ?
Hey, did you even know?
わかってんでしょ?
Are you realizing slow
隠し味の恋心
that the special taste is love I want to show?
苦味とか酸味とか
Bitter on my tongue, sour like a plum,
そういうのもたまにはいいわ
they all have a place inside a cake and love.
意地張りでワガママな そんな「魔法」使い
Stubborn by and by, with sweet magic I'll make you mine.
飛び出したい 翼をくれたね
You gave me wings to want to fly away,
そう、探し出したい 届けたい 人がいるから
to find and reach out to someone today.
駄々っ子置き去りにしたりしないと
I won't leave my childish side behind,
そっと秘めたんだ 愛したい 応えたい
holding this hidden wish in my mind.
自分自身のピュア 世界なんて 超えて行こう
Let's cross beyond the world with our pure heart!
見果てぬ世界のステア!
Ascending to an endless realm!
どんな場所でもいいよ どんな姿でもいいよ
No matter where we are, no matter what we wear,
追いかけたいんだ あの煌めきを
I want to chase that sparkling light out there.
希望 光 痛み 全て 抱きしめてもっと行こう
Embracing hope, light, and pain, let's move ahead!
ほら 繋げたい 広げたい 道があるから ここから始まる物語を
There's a path to connect and expand, a story starting here.
信じる力が奇跡起こすように この手を握って
Hold my hand so our belief creates a miracle.
一人じゃないから 君に魔法をかけるよ ウィギャンステルをおやじー!
We're not alone, I'll cast a spell on you. We can start our journey!
コラボさん 激烈カンヤ!
Collabo stage was super cool!
ありがとう！ホロウィッチ！すっごくかっこよかったよ！
Thank you! holoWitches, that was so cool!
コラボさんあれで全部かな? そうじゃない? デカイのが出てきそうな感じもしないし。
Is that all for the collab? Who knows, though it feels like something big might appear.
じゃあ、もう戦い終わりなのな? 今回はサクッと勝ててよかったな!
So the battles are already over? Good thing we won so easily this time!
いつもけっこう苦戦させられるもんね。
We usually have a pretty tough time, after all.
船長たちも魔法少女がいたに付いてきたってことかな? そうですね、もう何度も魔法使って戦ってますし。
Did the captains follow us because we're magical girls? Yeah, we've used magic to fight so many times.
魔法! ファンの皆さんもっとホロウィッチの魔法が見たいと思いますよ!
Magic! I'm sure all the fans want to see more of holoWitches' magic!
じゃあエリートの魔法一丁! 一丁かな?
Then how about an elite magic trick? Just one?
6人ってさっきやったし、今度は3人ずつチームに分かれてみる?
We already did six together, what if we split into teams of three?
賛成なら! まずはルーナたちがやるなら!
Agreed! Shall Luna's team go first?
じゃ、おてなみ拝見と行きましょう! がんばれー!
Let's see your skills then! Good luck!
せーの! ホロウィッチチームデラックス! ふるうぃっちゅー!
Ready, set! holoWitches Team Deluxe!
スイートマジック 作詞・作曲: Junky
[Title: Sweet Magic / Music by Junky]
甘くて幸せなこと 隠し味何にしよう
I'll make a treat so sweet and full of fun, but I wanna hide a little bit of love.
純粋な乙女心 甘い恋も絡めなくちゃ
Pure like a gem, a maiden's eager heart, gotta mix it all in.
切なさ重ねてミルフィーユ 酸味も積み上げタルト
Bake a layered mille-feuille and a sour tart.
苦味もチョコレートケーキ? 魔法かけた甘い奇跡
Make it bitter with a chocolate cake, miracles with a spell!
甘くて幸せなこと
Sweet and happy things,
隠し味何にしよう
What should our secret ingredient be?
純粋な乙女心
A pure maiden's heart,
甘い恋も絡めないっちゃ
Sweet romance intertwined.
切なさ重ねてミルフィーユ
Baking a layered mille-feuille with pain,
酸味も積み上げタルト
And a sour tart stacked high.
苦味もチョコレートケーキ魔法は
Bitter chocolate cake, casting a spell
かけた甘い奇跡
Of sweet miracles.
甘さは抑えてビターとか
Should I tone down the sweetness and go bitter?
ミルクなしのコーヒーとか
Or maybe coffee without milk?
甘いだけじゃ大人になれないの
If sweetness alone doesn't make me an adult,
そんなの絶対に絶対に嫌だ嫌だ嫌だ
I refuse, absolutely refuse, no no no!
ねえ上げようか甘い罠
Hey, shall I set a sweet trap?
ほら罠にしてあげる
Look, I'll make it a trap for you.
そんな魔法かけるから
Casting such magic upon you,
ちょっとだけ待たせたげるわ
I'll make you wait just a little bit.
たった一口が足りなくて
Just one bite isn't enough,
赤いイチゴみたい意地張って
Acting stubborn like a red strawberry.
甘いところなんて見せないわ
I won't show you my sweet side.
完璧に作るもん 一人でも、でも、でも
I'll make it perfectly, all by myself!
ねえ気づいてるんでしょ？
Hey, did you even know?
分かってるんでしょ？
Realizing it slowly,
隠し味の恋心
A secret ingredient of love.
苦みとか酸味とか
Bitter and sour,
そういうのもたまにはいいわ
Sometimes those are nice too.
意地張りで
Being stubborn
わがままと
And selfish,
そんな「甘い魔法」使い
Using such "sweet magic"!
スウィート スウィート スウィート マジック
Sweet, sweet, sweet magic,
Sweet, sweet, sweet magic!
尊い一口足りなくて
Just one precious bite isn't enough,
赤いイチゴ見たく意地張って
Acting stubborn like a red strawberry.
甘いところなんて見せないわ
I won't show you my sweet side.
甘いところなんて見せないわ完璧につくでも
Even if I make it perfectly...
一人でもでもでも
All by myself, still...
ねえ気づいてるんでしょ？
Hey, did you even know?
分かってるんでしょ？
Realizing it slowly,
隠し味の恋心
A secret ingredient of love.
苦みとか酸味とか
Bitter and sour,
そういうのもたまにはいいわ
Sometimes those are nice too.
意地張りとわがままと
Stubbornness and selfishness,
そんなのもたまにはいいわ
Sometimes that's okay too.
いじっぱりでわがままで
Being stubborn and selfish,
そんな甘い魔法を使う
Using such sweet magic!
スウィート スウィート スウィート マジック
Sweet, sweet, sweet magic,
Sweet, sweet, sweet magic!
チームラスター、素敵な魔法をありがとう！
Team Laster, thank you for the wonderful magic!
めっちゃよかったじゃん！こっちも頑張らないとな！
That was amazing! We've gotta do our best too!
せっかくだし、次はちょっと雰囲気変えてみない？
Since we have the chance, why don't we change the mood?
いいですね！
Sounds good!
じゃあ、
Then,
せーの！ホロウィッチ！チームアストラ！フルキャスト！
Ready, set! HoloWitch! Team Astra! Full cast!
空にある何かを見つめていたら
As I stared up at something in the sky,
それは星だって君が教えてくれた
You told me they were stars.
まるでそれは僕らみたいに寄り添ってる
Just like us, they nestle close together,
それを泣いたり笑ったり繋いでいく
Crying, laughing, and connecting them.
何十回何百回ぶつかり合って
Clashing tens and hundreds of times,
何十年何百年前昔の光が
A light from tens and hundreds of years ago—
星自身も忘れたころに僕らに届いている
Reaching us by the time the stars themselves forgot.
僕らに届いている
Reaching us...
僕ら見つめ合って手を取り合って同じ空輝くの
Hand in hand, shining under the same sky.
だって二人だって約束した遥か遠く
Because the two of us promised, far away,
終わらないベテルギウス
A never-ending Betelgeuse,
誰かに繋ぐ魔法
Magic that connects to someone.
僕らが手を取り合って進んでく
We take each other's hands and move forward,
辛い時だって泣かないって誓ったんだろ
Vowing not to cry even in times of pain.
遥か遠く終わらないベテルギウス
Far away, a never-ending Betelgeuse,
君にも見えるだろう
You can see it too,
祈りが
The prayer...
記憶をたどるたび蘇るよ君がいつだってそこに居てくれること
Every time I trace my memories, they revive—how you are always there.
空にある何かを見つめていたら 君が教えてくれた
As I stared up at something in the sky, you told me
まるでそれは 星の光と同じように
They were stars, just like the starlight.
今日にも泣いたり笑ったり繋いでいく
Crying, laughing, and connecting into today.
何十回 何百回 ぶつかり合って
Tens and hundreds of times we clashed,
何十年 何百年 昔の光が
A light from tens and hundreds of years ago
僕自身も忘れたころに
Reaches us just when we forgot about it ourselves,
僕らを照らしている
Shining down upon us.
僕ら見つけ合って 手繰り合って 同じ空
We found each other, pulling close under the same sky,
輝くのだって 二人だって 約束した
Promising we would shine together, just the two of us.
遥か遠く 終わらないベテルギウス
Far away, a never-ending Betelgeuse,
誰かに繋ぐ魔法
Magic that connects to someone.
どこまで いつまで 生きられるか
How far and how long can we keep living?
君が不安になるたびに強くなるんだ
Whenever you feel uneasy, I grow stronger.
大丈夫 僕が 横に いるよ 見えない
It's okay, I'm right beside you, connecting
線を繋ごう
The invisible lines.
僕ら見つけ合って 手繰り合って 同じ空
We found each other, pulling close under the same sky,
輝くのだって 二人だって 約束した
Promising we would shine together, just the two of us.
遥か遠く 終わらないベテルギウス
Far away, a never-ending Betelgeuse,
誰かに繋ぐ魔法
Magic that connects to someone.
僕ら肩並べて 手取り合って進んでく
Standing shoulder to shoulder, holding hands as we move forward,
辛い時だって 二人だって誓っただろ
We swore we'd face hard times together, didn't we?
遥か遠く 終わらないベテルギウス
Far away, a never-ending Betelgeuse,
君にも見えるだろう 祈りが
Surely you can see this prayer too.
空にある何かを見つめていたら
As I stared up at something in the sky,
それは星だって君が教えてくれた
You told me they were stars.
チームアストラの魔法も すごくいい雰囲気でしたね！
Team Astra's magic had such a wonderful atmosphere!
これ思ったよりきっつい…
This is way tougher than I thought...
ちょっちょ、みんな大丈夫？
Hey, hey, is everyone okay?
はあ、なーが、魔法を使いすぎてる。
Haa, Nanga, you're using too much magic.
これじゃみんなの力が持たないよ。
At this rate, everyone won't have enough power.
大丈夫。
It's okay.
まだやれるから。はい。
I can still do it. Here.
この人を助けるためには。でも…
To help this person. But...
もっと見せてください、ホロウィッチ！
Show us more, HoloWitches!
え？ もしかしてMCのお姉さん？
Eh? Could you be the MC big sis?
魔法、魔法を！魔法、魔法魔法魔法、魔法見せて！
Magic, magic! Show us magic, magic, magic, magic!
ねぇ魔法を、魔法少女の魔法を見せて！
Hey, magic, show us the magical girl's magic!
お、お姉さん、いけない！ホロウィッチこれ以上は！
W-Wait, big sis, stop! HoloWitches, no more than this!
いけない？だめなの？
No? Is it no good?
どうしてだめなの？
Why is it no good?
魔法少女でしょ？
You're magical girls, right?
見せて！使って！
Show us! Use it!
魔法！魔法！魔法！
Magic! Magic! Magic!
この感じ…なんか来るよ！やばいのが！
This feeling... Something's coming! Something dangerous!
いいな、魔法。魔法少女。
Must be nice, magic. Magical girls.
私もなりたかった。ずっと、ずっとずっとずっとずっとずっとずっ…
I wanted to be one too. Always, always, always, always, always, alwa—
あなたたちみたいな魔法少女になりたかった！なりたかったのに！
I wanted to become a magical girl like you all! Even though I wanted to!
なのにさ！今の私は惨めで、ブサイクで！
Even so! The me right now is pathetic and ugly!
なにも…
Nothing...
愛して 愛して 愛して
Love me, love me, love me
はるか遠い遠い昔 巻かれた首輪
Far, far away, in a distant past, a coiling collar
人が欲しい 人が欲しいと叫ぶ呪いの首輪
"I want people, I want people," cried the cursed collar
怒らないで 見捨てないで どこもいかないで (ねえ)
Don't get angry, don't abandon me, don't go anywhere (Hey)
強く締めると 吐くまで締めると
Strangling me tightly, until I could throw up,
人がいない いない と
Whenever no one, no one is around.
いい成績でしょう
Nice grades, right?
ねえねえ いい子でしょう
Hey, hey, aren't I a good kid?
かわいい子でしょう
Aren't I a cute kid?
ねえねえ 良い子でしょう 苦しいねえ
Hey, hey, I'm a good kid, right? It hurts, hey.
愛して 愛して 愛して もっともっと
Love me, love me, love me, more and more,
愛して 愛して 狂おしいほどに
Love me, love me, so much that it's maddening.
苦しい 離さない 苦しい もっともっと ねえ
It hurts, won't let go, hurts, more and more, hey.
止められない ah
It can't be stopped, ahh...
愛して 愛して 愛して もっともっと愛して
Love me, love me, love me, more and more, love me,
愛して 狂おしいほどに 苦しい 苦しい
Love me, so much that it's maddening, it hurts, it hurts.
呪縛を 解いて 解いてね
Break, break this binding spell, okay?
止められない ah 止められない ah
It can't be stopped, ahh... it can't be stopped, ahh...
止められない ah
It can't be stopped, ahh...
身体 身体 大きくなっても 小さい首輪
Even if your body grows big, the collar remains small.
苦しくなる 足りなくなって 人が 人が足りない
It becomes painful, not enough, people, people are not enough.
クラスの 誰にも 負けない キレイな いい子 で し ょ う
I won't lose to anyone in my class, aren't I a lovely kid?
あの子より どの子より 誰も彼も 私を見てよ
Not that kid, not any other kid; everyone, come and look at me!
体育館裏 あなたに告白を
Behind the gymnasium, when I told you of my love...
嘘みたいな で し ょ う
Doesn't it seem like a lie?
あなたが 好き な の 汚い あなた が
I like you, you who are so filthy.
愛して 愛して 愛して 全部 あげる あなたに
Love me, love me, love me, I'll give you everything.
あなたに 全部 背負って もらう よ
I'll have you shoulder everything for me.
足りない あなた が 足りない 離さないよ ah
You are not enough, not enough, I won't let go, ahh...
ごめんなさい
I'm so sorry.
愛して 愛して 愛して もっともっと
Love me, love me, love me, more and more,
愛して 愛して 狂おしいほどに
Love me, love me, so much that it's maddening.
苦しい 離さない 苦しい もっともっと ねえ
It hurts, won't let go, hurts, more and more, hey.
幸せ な の ah 幸せ な の ah
This is happiness, ahh... this is happiness, ahh...
愛して 愛して 愛して もっともっと
Love me, love me, love me, more and more,
愛して 愛して 狂おしいほどに
Love me, love me, so much that it's maddening.
苦しい 本当に 苦しい 苦しい
It hurts, truly hurts, it hurts, it hurts,
呪縛を 解いて 解いてね 止められない
Break, break this binding spell, it can't be stopped...
幸せなのは ah
This happiness is, ahh...
お姉さんが…
An older sister...
コラップサーに取り込まれてる！
...is being absorbed by the collapser!
悲しい気持ちが大きくなりすぎて、コラップサーの力が増しちゃったんだ。
Her sadness grew too big, and it made the collapser's power increase!
えー、待て待て待て！
Wait, wait, wait!
このショーってあれでしょ？お姉さんが魔法少女好きすぎて、それでこういうの作っちゃったってやつでしょ？
This show is that thing, right? Where an older sister loved magical girls so much she made something like this?
そう、だから、猫たちが魔法使ってることたくさん見せられたら、不安とか悲しいとか、そういうの無くせるかもって…
Yeah, so if we could show everyone cats using magic a lot, maybe we could get rid of anxiety and sadness...
あ、逆か。逆？
Ah, is it the opposite? The opposite?
いや、あの姉さんさ、マジで魔法少女が好きで、魔法少女になりたくて、でもなれなくて諦めたわけじゃん。
No, that sister really loved magical girls, wanted to be one, but couldn't and gave up, right?
そっか。好きだけど、本当にめちゃくちゃ好きだけど、
I see. She loves it, she really, really loves it, but...
でも、だからこそ実際に見ると、自分はそう慣れなかったんだって思って、好きなはずなのに苦しいって感じちゃうんだ。
Because of that, seeing it in reality makes her think she couldn't become one, and so even though she loves it, it feels painful.
あの人自身気づいてなかったのかも。大好きな魔法少女のショーを見られたら、また元気を取り戻せるかもって。
Maybe she herself didn't realize it. Thinking that if she watched her beloved magical girl show, she might regain her energy.
だからのコラップサー。こうなるって分かってて、それでもあえてお姉さんにショーを見せたのか…！
That's why it's a collapser. Knowing it would turn out like this, you still dared to show the show to the older sister...!
なんて…なんでこうなっちゃったの？
Why... why did it turn out like this?
なんて苦しいの止まらないの？
Why won't this pain stop?
何をしてても、何考えてても…
No matter what I do, no matter what I think...
なんて…なんで楽しいより苦しいほうが大きくなっちゃうの？
Why... why does the pain grow bigger than the joy?
ホロウィッチ！
Horowitch!
じゃあ、このコメント…リスナーのみんなの…
Then, these comments... everyone in the chat...
みんなが見てる人、一人ひとりが、みこたちのこと応援してくれてる。
Everyone watching, every single person, is cheering us on.
がんばれって言ってくれてる。
They're telling us to do our best.
どなたたちだけじゃないのら。お姉さんのことも、がんばってほしい、幸せになってほしいって思ってくれてる。
And not just for us. They want the older sister to do her best and be happy too.
背中も、心も…心から押してくれてる。
They're pushing us forward, from the bottom of their hearts...
みんなの気持ちで、みんなの心が…
With everyone's feelings, everyone's hearts...
ホロが輝く！
Holo shines!
これだけ背中を押されたら…飛び込んでくしかないよね、みんな！
With this much support... we have no choice but to dive in, everyone!
なんだかこっち敵多いけどさ…
There sure are a lot of enemies on our side...
しょうがないね。
Well, it can't be helped.
チェンジ！みこべるノート！
Change! Mikobel Note!
うん
Yeah.
ルナもやるなら
If Luna is going to do it,
チェンジ！
change!
あまいのだ！
It's sweet!
ありがと、一味の君たち。本当…いい男たちだねぇ！
Thank you, my crew. You really are... such fine men!
チェンジ！がんばりなっ！
Change! Do your best!
チェンジ！
Change!
オッケー。ありがと。
Okay. Thank you.
お待たせぇーっ！チェンジ！
Kept you waiting! Change!
よし、成り切っていきまっしょ！
All right, let's play our parts to the fullest!
あなたはどうして魔法少女になりたかったの？
Why did you want to become magical girls?
どうしてって……いろんな魔法が使えて、素敵で、かっこよくって……
Why... because you can use all kinds of magic, it's wonderful, it's cool...
うん。そんで、魔法少女になってさ、どんなことがしたかった？
Yeah. And once you became a magical girl, what did you want to do?
それは……お姉さんの好きな魔法少女はどんなことをしてたのだ？
That is... what did the magical girls you older sisters like do?
ずっと…助けてた。魔法で、素敵に、かっこよく。
They were always... helping people. Magically, wonderfully, and coolly.
そう。そこが魔法少女のいいとこだよね。
That's right. That's the best part about being a magical girl.
そこが好きになったならあなたは、魔法少女になりたかったっていうより、誰かの力になれる誰かになりたかったんじゃない？
If you fell in love with that, maybe you didn't want to become a magical girl so much as you wanted to be someone who could help others.
誰かの力になれる…誰か……
Someone who can help others...
どんな小さなことでも、ちょっとしたことでも、誰かの力になれるなら、それって魔法少女と一緒じゃん。
No matter how small or trivial, if you can help someone, isn't that the same as a magical girl?
お姉さんが好きだった魔法少女は、きっとそれを教えてくれてたのだ。
The magical girls you older sisters loved must have taught you that.
そうそう。だからさ、魔法が使えるかどうかは関係ないんじゃない？
That's right. So whether you can use magic or not doesn't really matter, does it?
あなたが好きだった魔法少女が教えてくれた、誰かの力になれるのが素敵でかっこいいっていう気持ち。
The feeling that being able to help someone—which the magical girl you loved taught you—is wonderful and cool.
それがあなたのホロ。あなたの一番のお宝。
That is your Holo. Your greatest treasure.
私……私の…コラップさんの力が弱まってる！
My... Colaps's power is weakening!
今だ！ホロウィッチ！
Now! Holowitch!
チェンジ！ホロウィッチセキ！
Change! Holowitch Seki!
大丈夫ですか？
Are you alright?
うん。ありがとう。それと……ごめんなさい。
Yeah. Thank you. And... I'm sorry.
あなたたちを巻き込んでしまって
You got dragged into all of this...
いいのいいの 気にしないで！
It's fine, it's fine! Don't worry about it!
先女たちがホロウィッチになったのは夢オチした人を助けるためなんだから
After all, the reason we Senjo became HoloWitch is to help people who've fallen into dream-ends.
そっか
I see...
あなたたちみんな本当に魔法少女なんだね
You're all really magical girls, huh?
魔法が使えるからじゃなくて誰かの力になれたらって思うその心が
Not because we can use magic, but because we want to be of help to someone...
私もなれるかな
I wonder if I can be like that too.
誰かの力になれる誰かに
To be able to help someone, to someone...
ううん
Hmm.
みんなはどう思う？
What do you all think?
だってお姉さんならきっと大丈夫なのだ
Because if it's big sis, I'm sure it'll be fine!
頑張ってみる
I'll try my best.
ありがとう ホロウィッチ！
Thank you, HoloWitch!
あの人の心現実の世界に帰れたんだ
That person's heart was able to return to the real world.
もう安心だよ ホロウィッチ
We can rest easy now, HoloWitch.
そっか
I see.
よかったあ！
I'm so glad!
これでめでたしめでたし！
And they all lived happily ever after!
でもいいんだけどせっかくホロキャス繋がっててリスナーの皆さんが見てくれてるんだし
That's fine and all, but since Holocast is connected and all our listeners are watching...
ここはやっぱり歌う？歌っちゃう？歌っちゃうのだ！
Shouldn't we sing here? Sing? Let's sing!
アール ラグ、戻るのちょっと後になってもいい？
R-Rug, is it okay if we return a little later?
もちろん
Of course.
じゃあ僕らは先に戻って準備してるから好きなだけ楽しんでから戻ってきてね
Then we'll head back first and get ready, so have as much fun as you like before coming back!
うん
Yeah.
THE STAGE
[Title: THE STAGE]
いつもの一日から抜け出して
I leap out of the same routine I'm living day by day
目が覚めるような冒険の舞台へ
To that astounding stage with all adventures waiting
回る地球儀を目印に
My eyes are set on this globe, we can see it rotate
さあ今会いに行こう
And then "hello," we'll say
特別な一日に
A special day is a heartbeat away
緑萌ゆる新しい季節に
Greenery, shining view As a brand-new season has begun
一人見つめたブルーライト
There was me, staring at that blue light tone
顔も知らない友達にも満たないクラスメイト
And I don't even know all their faces Not yet friends, but classmates only
想定外の暮らし
It's nothing near what life should be
妄想した理想と真反対に淡々と過ぎる毎日
Contrast with that Ideal I had imagined in my mind as Days unfold and pass me by
でもやっと会えるね
But now, at last, we're meeting up
想像と現実が交わって高鳴る胸抑えられない
Reality and visions merging So, my heart is pounding and I cannot hold it back
約束の場所は
We promised to meet and hang out
夢見ていた場所
In that place I've been dreaming 'bout
忘れられない一日が今始まる
A day we won't forget is now about to start Opening with a spark
待ちに待った今日は特別な日
Matching dreams i had, visions and this day convene
日常から少しはみ出して
Now i step outside the pace of my routine
ほらシャッターを切って写し出せば
And, if i take a picture, a piece of this scene
零れるような笑顔ばかり
Ah, come what may So many smiles on the faces i see
「行こうぜ」誰かが言って飛び乗った coaster
Let's get on that, someone said, and we hopped on a coaster
お揃いのヘッドフォン
The matching headbands we have put on
尊い瞬間 spill out overflow and still accrue
Priceless moments spill out, overflow, and still accrue
待ち時間さえも愛おしく思える
Even the waiting time, you know, is so dear to me too
どこへ向かっているんだっけ
Where should i be heading up to now?
雲の上を歩くよう
I'm walking like i'm on a cloud
おっとおかしいな
Oh, it's almost uncanny
気が付けば過ぎている時間
As i'm noticing how quickly time is passing by
そして太陽が沈んだ街を飾る
And the sun, on its way down Unveiled a city view
光が織りなすパレードに
Lights are shining on so bright, a parade of hues
心奪われかみしめる
I'll remember, forever My soul is enthused
ああ本当にここにこられてよかったな
I'm so very glad i could come here My heart's deeply moved
待ちに待った今日は特別な日
Matching dreams i had, visions and this day convene
日常から少しはみ出して
I burst out of my everyday same routine
ほらシャッターを切っても映せない
And if i take a picture, nothing will appear
想い出がいつでも待っている
Those memories are forevermore waiting here
春も夏も秋も冬もこの場所で見つけたい顔が
Every season to come, they revolve on and on In this very place, the smiles we've encountered, all
ひらひらといくつも積もっていくさあ次は何処へ行こうか
Flutter down and accumulate inside my heart So, when can i see you again the next time around?
太陽が沈んだ街を飾る
And the sun, on its way down Unveiled a city view
光が織りなすパレードに心奪われ
Lights are shining on so bright, a parade of hues
かみしめる ああ本当にここにこれてよかったな
I'm so very glad i could come here My heart's deeply moved
待ちに待った今日は特別な日
Matching dreams i had, visions and this day convene
いつもの日から飛び出して
I burst out of my everyday same routine
ほらシャッターを切っても映せない
And if i take a picture, nothing will appear
想い出がいつでも待っている
Those memories are forevermore waiting here
春も夏も秋も冬もこの場所で見つけたい顔が
Every season to come, they revolve on and on In this very place, the smiles we've encountered, all
ひらひらといくつも積もっていくさあ次は何処へ行こうか
Flutter down and accumulate inside my heart So, when can i see you again the next time around?
当たり前から抜け出して
Step out of my regular day-to-day
限界のない冒険の旅へ
To that eternal stage with all adventures waiting
回る地球儀を目印にさあ今会いに行こう
My eyes are set on this globe, we can see it rotate And then "hello," we'll say
すごい！あれだけ魔法使ったのに、
Incredible! Even after using all that magic,
なんか逆に元気出てきてない？
somehow we're feeling even more energized, right?
やっぱさ、あれじゃん！みんなから応援もらえたからじゃん！
I mean, right? It's because we got everyone's support!
うん！みんながいるから、僕らもこうして頑張れる！
Yeah! Because you're all here, we can work hard like this!
いつも応援してくれてるみんなも、
And for everyone who always supports us,
誰かの力になれる誰かってことなならね？
that means you're someone who can be a strength to others, right?
そうそう、シオンたちの力になってくれてる！
That's right, you've become our strength!
じゃあ、リスナーの皆さんも、魔法少女ってことで…
So, to all our listeners, you're magical girls too...
ん？ね？
Huh? Right?
みんな！いつもありがとう！
Everyone! Thank you always!
魔法少女になった僕たちのこと、これからも応援よろしくね！
Please keep supporting us now that we've become magical girls!
みんな！魔法少女の巫女たちどうだったかな？
Everyone! How were the magical girl micos?
エリートになった？これからも応援よろしくね！
Did we become elite? Please keep supporting us!
みんな！今日はありがと！
Everyone! Thank you today!
ホロウィッチの魔法がみんなにも届いてたら嬉しいな！
I'd be so happy if holoWitches' magic reached everyone too!
君たちのパワーでセクシーな魔法少女になれました！
With your power, we became sexy magical girls!
これからもたくさん応援してくださいね！
Please keep supporting us a lot!
みんな！どうだった？楽しんでくれたかな？
Everyone! How was it? Did you enjoy it?
いつもいつもシオンたちのこと応援してくれてありがとう！
Thank you so much for always supporting Shion and the others!
うわあ、緊張した！
Whoa, I was so nervous!
けどみんなの応援に元気をもらって乗り切れたよ！
But thanks to everyone's support giving me energy, I got through it!
本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
みんなから力をもらえたおかげで、
Thanks to getting power from everyone,
もう一曲行けそうなら…
if it looks like we can do one more song...
みんな、ホロウィッチの魔法、最後まで見ていってくだせい！
Everyone, please watch holoWitches' magic all the way to the end!
最後の曲聴いてください！
Please listen to our final song!
せーの！おーいぇーい！
Ready, set! Oh yeah!
キラキラ 宝石みたいに輝いてる
Glitter, glitter, shining like jewels,
夢の結晶 みんなの宝物
A crystallization of dreams, our cherished treasure.
時々見失っちゃうこともあるけど
Time to time we might lose sight of it,
溢れ出した光が僕を呼んだよ
But the overflowing light calls out to me.
絶対大丈夫
It'll be alright, for sure.
ただまっすぐでいることも楽じゃない日もあるよね
Walking straight isn't always easy every day, you know.
諦めも苦しみも隠さなくていい 心解き放とう
You don't have to hide despair or pain, set your heart free.
夢を歌おう (はい！) 魔法に乗せて
Let's sing our dreams (Yes!) riding on magic,
何度も立ち上がる 君と一緒に進んでいく
Rising up again and again, moving forward together with you.
夢は 夢は まだ終わらない
Our dreams, our dreams are not over yet.
未来を取り戻そう
Let's take back the future.
何度だって笑って もう一回歩きはじめよう
Laugh no matter how many times, and start walking once more.
ホロウィッチ on your side
holoWitches on your side,
夢の先へ
Beyond the dream.
ワクワクするような日々 と夢の結晶 思い出して
Remember those exciting days and the crystallization of dreams.
魔法を唱えてみたら ドキドキするような君の物語
When you try chanting a spell, your story makes your heart race.
もう一度胸に キラリ光りだすんだよ
Sparkling brightly in your chest once again.
頑張っていても うまくいかない日のほうが多く感じちゃったりするよね
Sometimes it feels like days when hard work doesn't pay off happen more often.
その不安も 悲しみも 抱えないで 一人じゃない
Don't carry that anxiety and sorrow alone, you're not by yourself.
希望の種を 明日に蒔いたら
If we sow the seeds of hope for tomorrow,
一番に輝く 綺麗な花が咲くよ
The most dazzling, beautiful flower will bloom first.
夢を歌おう (はい！) 魔法に乗せて
Let's sing our dreams (Yes!) riding on magic,
何度も立ち上がる 君と一緒に進んでいく
Rising up again and again, moving forward together with you.
夢は夢は
Dreams are...
まだ終わらない
Not over yet.
未来を取り戻そう
Let's take back the future.
何度だって笑って
Laughing no matter how many times,
もう一回歩きはじめよう
let's start walking once again.
ホロウィッチ on your side
Holowitch on your side,
夢の先へ
ahead of our dreams.
あれ？
Huh?
私…
Me...
あ、先輩、すみません！
Ah, Senpai, sorry!
こっちの作業はまだ終わってなくて、
My work here isn't done yet,
だよね？ あれ多分期日延ばしても後ろに影響出ないと思うから、こっちで話し通しとくね。
Right? I think extending the deadline won't affect anything later, so I'll handle explaining it.
え？ いいんですか！？
Eh? Are you sure!?
どうしようかと思ってたんです、本当。
I really didn't know what to do.
いいよ、いいよ。
It's fine, it's fine.
お互い無理せず、でも全力で頑張ろう、フルキャストでね！
Let's not overdo it, but do our best with the full cast!
フルキャスト？ って何です？
Full cast? What do you mean?
頑張るぞって言う、おまじない、かな？
An incantation like 'Let's do our best', maybe?
キミに魔法をかけるよ
I'll cast a spell on you,
聞かせるよ Magic
and let you hear the Magic.
始まると告げる 衝動が響く
The impulse announcing the start echoes,
気づいた 時がいつだってスタートラインなんだ
the moment I realized it was always the starting line.
何ものでもなかった日を超えたのは 見つけた私だけのちっぽけな輝きの日々
Surpassing the days when I was nobody, were the days of my own small, shining light I found.
どうして私だけうまくいかないんだろう
Why is it that only I can't get things right?
すれ違いのすべてが まぶしく見えるけどね
Though all the passing moments look so dazzling,
君に見つけてほしくて
I wanted you to find me.
なりたい私になる
I'll become the me I want to be.
生きてこう 空がかなえたい 掴みたい 夢があるから
Let's live on, because the sky has dreams we want to fulfill and grasp.
抱え込んだ日のことも すべて踏み出すんだ 信じる力が奇跡を起こすように
Stepping forward from everything in those burdened days, so that the power of belief works miracles.
キミに魔法をかけるよ
I'll cast a spell on you,
聞かせるよ Magic
and let you hear the Magic.
叶えたいと願わない願い それぞれが等しく曲がれてく世界で
In a world where unexpressed wishes to make things come true are each equally distorted,
何を求めて 歩き続けるんだろう いつんなそんなことばかり迷うけど
What am I seeking as I keep walking? Though I always get lost in such thoughts,
君がくれたこの空が 冷めない場所をくれたね
This sky you gave me gave me an uncooling place.
照らしたい 届けたい 人がいるから
Because there are people I want to illuminate and reach,
たった一人置いてかない 真っ白いと 好きと言いたい 自分自身の真実だって
I won't leave a single person behind. Wanting to say I love pure white, that's my own truth.
世界なんて これでいいみたい
It seems the world is fine like this.
どんな場所でもいいよ どんな姿でもいい 追いかけたいんだ あのきらめきを
Any place is fine, any form is fine, I want to chase that sparkle.
希望の光さえ 全て抱きしめてもっていこう
Let's embrace even the light of hope and take it with us.
こらえたい 広げたい 道があるから
Because there is a path I want to hold back and expand.
ここから始まる物語を 一緒にゆこう 信じる力が奇跡を起こすように
Let's go together into the story starting from here, so that the power of belief works miracles.
ホロテン盛り上げて 一人じゃないから
Liven up Holo-ten, because you're not alone,
キミに魔法をかけるよ 聞かせるよ Magic
I'll cast a spell on you, and let you hear the Magic.
きみに魔法をかけるよ we cast a spell on your dream!!
I'll cast a spell on you, we cast a spell on your dream!!
はじまりを告げる衝動が響く
The impulse announcing the beginning echoes
気づいた時がいつだってスタートラインなんだ
Whenever you realize it is always the starting line
何者でもなかった日々を変えたのは
What changed those days when I was nobody
見つけたばかりのちっちゃな輝きの原石
Was just a newly found tiny rough diamond of brilliance
「どうして私だけうまくいかないんだろう」
"Why is it that only things don't go well for me?"
自分以外の全てが眩しくみえるけど
Everything besides myself looks dazzling, but
ねえきみに見つけてほしくて
Hey, I want you to find me
なりたい私になる今こそ
Now is the time to become the me I want to be
そうだ！叶えたい掴みたい夢があるから
That's right! Because there's a dream I want to fulfill and grasp
塞ぎこんだ日のことも連れて踏み出すんだ
Taking even the closed-off days along, I step forward
信じる力が奇跡起こすように
So that the power to believe works miracles
きみに魔法をかけるよ
I'll cast a spell on you
we cast a spell on your dream!!
叶った望みと叶わない願い
Fulfilled hopes and unfulfilled wishes
それぞれが等しく流れてくる世界で
In a world where each equally flows by
何を求めて歩き続けるんだろう
What am I searching for as I keep walking?
そんなことばかり迷うけれど
I hesitate over such things, but
きみがくれたこの空が
This sky you gave me
消えない翼をくれたね
Gave me unyielding wings
そうだ！照らしたいとどめたい人がいるから
That's right! Because there's someone I want to shine upon and cherish
誰ひとり置いたりしないとそう決めたんだ
I decided I wouldn't leave anyone behind
愛したい応えたい自分自身のfeel
My own feel of wanting to love and respond
正解なんて越えてこう
Let's surpass even correct answers
未体験のstage!!
To an unprecedented stage!!
どんな場所でもいいよ どんな姿でもいい
Any place is fine, any form is fine
追いかけたいんだあのきらめきを
I want to chase after that brilliance
「希望」
"Hope"
「苦悩」
"Anguish"
「光」
"Light"
「痛み」
"Pain"
「力」
"Power"
「全て」
"Everything"
抱きしめて持っていこう
Let's embrace them all and carry on
ほら繋げたい広げたい可能性(みち)があるから
Look, because there are possibilities we want to connect and expand
ここから始まる物語を一緒に行こう
Let's go together into the story starting from here
きみに魔法をかけるよ we cast a spell on your dream!!
I'll cast a spell on you, we cast a spell on your dream!!
はじまりを告げる衝動が響く
The impulse announcing the beginning echoes
気づいた時がいつだってスタートラインなんだ
Whenever you realize it is always the starting line
何者でもなかった日々を変えたのは
What changed those days when I was nobody
見つけたばかりのちっちゃな輝きの原石
Was just a newly found tiny rough diamond of brilliance
「どうして私だけうまくいかないんだろう」
"Why is it that only things don't go well for me?"
自分以外の全てが眩しくみえるけど
Everything besides myself looks dazzling, but
ねえきみに見つけてほしくて
Hey, I want you to find me
なりたい私になる今こそ
Now is the time to become the me I want to be
そうだ！叶えたい掴みたい夢があるから
That's right! Because there's a dream I want to fulfill and grasp
塞ぎこんだ日のことも連れて踏み出すんだ
Taking even the closed-off days along, I step forward
信じる力が奇跡起こすように
So that the power to believe works miracles
きみに魔法をかけるよ
I'll cast a spell on you
we cast a spell on your dream!!
叶った望みと叶わない願い
Fulfilled hopes and unfulfilled wishes